Jing Lin!
景林
Where is the doctor?
府医还没有到吗
He's on his way to find the doctor.
景林去请大夫了
It's raining cats and dogs.
外面的雨下得太大
He must be held up on the road.
估计是耽误了
No.
不行
He would
再这样下去
bleed to death.
他会失血过多的
Sir,
管家
get me hot water and bandages.
备热水和纱布
Yes, ma'am.
是
Usually, I use these tools
这些工具
to tend
都是我
dead bodies.
招呼死人的时候用的
There is no other choice now.
但事急从权
Please forgive me.
你多担待
He's burning.
他怎么这么烫
Sir,
管家
go to see if
你去看一下
Jing Lin is back.
景林到哪儿了
Tell me once when he is.
到了之后你跟我说
Yes, ma'am.
是
You saved my life. Again.
你又救了我一次
Tears are useless.
眼泪没有任何用处
Totally!
没有任何用处
Huo'e will not die for nothing.
火蛾不能白死
Shen Du
沈渡
will pay for it.
会受到应有的惩罚
And Huo'e...
而火蛾
will return to the land of living!
终将复活
Your Majesty,
陛下
Your Highness,
太皇太后
the news has spread
襄安城一夜之间
over Xiang'an that Lord Shen
已经传遍
was attacked
都说沈大阁领
by Chen Huo'e in the street,
昨日被这陈火蛾
and is
当街刺杀
severely injured.
重伤不治
I remember, Chancellor Lai
当初来中丞
promised that
可是言之凿凿
Chen Huo'e was already executed.
说陈火蛾已经伏法
But how could a commander
可堂堂的朝廷命官
be injured by a dead criminal
竟被一个已死之人
before the public?
重伤于百姓面前
More than a simple mistake
这何止是
in criminal investigation system,
缉凶审案出了纰漏
but a humiliation
这简直是在
for the empire!
打我大苍王朝的脸
Ma'am,
英王
we all know that
人人都知来中丞
Mr Lai is devoted.
对我大苍是忠心耿耿
Imperial Inspectorate too,
御察司更是令行禁止
it has always been
一直以来
representing the prestige
可都是我大苍的
of our empire.
威严所在啊
Mr Lai is known as
来中丞可是
the Dark Demon.
人人惧怕的黑罗刹
And all criminals will succumb,
御察司更是但有进入
once they are caught by Mr Lai.
未有不从
But Chen Huo'e has escaped
如今陈火蛾
from the II several times.
几次三番从御察司逃脱
It makes me wonder
很难不让人怀疑
whether it's caused by
来中丞在这件事情当中
Mr Lai's negligence
到底是办事不力
or assistance.
还是推波助澜
Your Highness,
太皇太后明鉴
Chen Huo'e truly died
陈火蛾确已在御察司
during the committal.
受刑讯而死
I already presented
审案卷宗
dossier of the case and
和陈火蛾口供遗物
her confession and belongings.
臣已悉数呈上
But I've heard that
只是臣听闻
although she's executed,
那陈火蛾虽被斩首
she can somehow return from the dead.
却仍有死而复生之能
Rumour has it that
百姓们纷纷传说
one day,
陈火蛾总有一天
she will be back.
还会归来
Nonsense.
无稽之谈
Lady Xu,
徐内司
read the file.
拿出来吧
Your Highness,
内卫府大阁领沈渡谨奏
I, Shen Du, found out that Chen Huo'e
微臣查获陈火蛾
had situs inversus.
乃世间罕见之镜像人
I already caught and beheaded her.
已将其当场缉拿斩首
She will never come back again.
世上从此再无陈火蛾
[Situs inversus.]
镜像之人
So,
这可是
she can escape
陈火蛾当年
from dead so many times.
屡次逃脱的秘密吗
Mr Lai, you interrogated her yourself,
来中丞你可是亲自刑讯
yet you didn't find out
竟未发现
her little secret.
陈火蛾有镜像之异
I'm sorry to miss it.
臣失职
Missed?
是失职呢
Or, you think
还是觉得
you can hide it from me?
不必上报哀家呀
I would never!
微臣不敢
I wouldn't hide
微臣万死
anything
也不敢有隐瞒
from you, Your Highness.
太皇太后之心啊
Well,
看来
it's time we find another prestige
这大苍的威严所在
representation of the empire.
该变一变了
Although you didn't intentionally
来中丞你放虎归山
make a mistake,
虽是无意
a criminal slipped through your fingers.
但却犯了失察之罪
I'll dock a year's wage of yours,
罚俸一年
and stop the circus you put out
你平时那套出行的
every time
唬人仪仗
you go out.
也撤了吧
Thank you for your mercy.
谢太皇太后开恩
Lady Xu,
徐内司
fetch the best court doctors
安排最好的御医
and medicines
最好的药
for Mr Shen Du.
务必让沈爱卿早日康复
Yes, ma'am.
是
[Lai Luozhi made a serious mistake!]
犯了这么大的错
Yet he just lost only a year's wage.
居然只是罚俸一年
Mother is too
母后对来中丞
kind to him!
可真是怜爱
Your Highness, why didn't you
英王殿下既有异议
just express
方才为何
your objection directly?
不在朝堂上提出
What did you say?
张相你什么意思
Mr Zhang,
张相
Your Highness,
皇姐
as a heinous criminal Chen Huo'e is,
陈火蛾罪大恶极
mother knows what's the best.
母后自有决断
We should not openly discuss
还是莫要在这里
her decisions like this.
妄议的好
You are right.
贤王说得有道理
It's so indiscreet of me.
是老臣草率了
Stop it, hypocrisy.
就你惯会做好人
You lost a lot of blood
流了那么多血
and had a high fever last night.
昨夜又发高热
Wake up, please.
你可千万要醒过来
I haven't
我还没有
cleared the name of your family.
帮你们沈家翻案呢
What are you doing here?
你怎么又来了
If they caught you, you could be killed.
被抓住你就没命了
I promised to buy you
我说好了要给你带
the fried rice ball.
西市的蹴鞠丸子
I squashed some of them
虽然进来的时候
when I got in,
被压瘪了一点点
but the taste is still the same.
但味道应该还不错
Try it.
你快尝尝
I don't have any money, now.
我身上没有钱
Here, take this.
把这个送给你吧
I don't want your money.
我不要你的钱
What do you think I am? A maid?
你当我是送菜的小厮吗
No. I just...
我不是 我
My father gave me this whistle as a gift.
这哨子是我爹送给我的
Look,
你看
my family name is carved in it.
上面有个沈字
I should go now,
我先走了
or, they will get me.
不然他们又来抓我了
Will you come back?
你还会回来吗
Definitely!
当然
Someday,
总有一天
I will clear your name
我会帮沈家翻案
and get you out.
光明正大地接你出去
The prison is a living hell,
你在罪容所
yet you still clawed your way
那么艰难的光景
out of there.
都能熬过来
Today,
这一次
you can also extricate
你也一定可以
yourself from illness.
逢凶化吉的
[It's you.]
原来真的是你
You can do it.
一定可以的
Even fell ill,
沈大阁领
the Shen Du I know
就算生病了
would act like it's nothing
也一定要精精神神的
and put up nice clothes.
换一身清爽的衣服
It may
说不定
facilitate his recovery.
还能好得更快一些
I'm so happy to know that.
幸好是你
I already stitched him up.
伤口我都缝过了
And he's lying here
他躺在这里
just like other corpses
跟别的尸体
I examined before.
也没有什么两样
I've examined so many male bodies,
男尸我都解剖那么多了
I'm not afraid to change his clothes.
我还怕给他换衣服吗
[He hides this rattan piggy]
他夜夜将这藤编小猪
[under his pillow.]
放在枕下
[The handwriting is beautiful.]
信笺字迹娟秀
[It must be]
想来
[written by]
定是出自他
[the girl in his heart.]
念念不忘的女子
Don't worry,
你放心
I'll not bother you with my feelings.
我不会缠着你不放的
You saved my life,
你救了我
and I take care of you.
我看护你
We are even.
我们两个算是扯平了
After the expiration of our agreement,
等三月期满
I'll leave you as we agreed.
我便如约与你和离
What?
三个月
Agreement?
如约和离
[You serious?]
我听到了什么
Chuichui.
垂垂
Xing.
六娘
Why are you here?
你怎么来了
After all things happened,
出了这么大的事
how could I not?
我能不来吗
This morning,
今日早朝之后
everybody says that
六部都在传
The White Death was
白无常
severely injured by Chen Huo'e,
被陈火蛾重伤不治
and is going to die.
是要咽气了吗
He did hurt pretty bad.
他是伤得很重
But...
但是吧
But what?
但是什么呀
You're killing me.
你要急死我了
Xing,
六娘
what happened between you two?
你跟白无常到底怎么了
Nothing.
没什么
Till now,
到了这个时候
you're still holding out on me.
你还想瞒着我
You aren't a real couple, are you?
你们是假夫妻
Chuichui, please keep it secret for me.
垂垂你千万替我保密啊
I didn't want to do it.
我也是迫不得已的
Did he threaten you?
是不是沈渡威胁你了
It must be him!
肯定是
In three months,
三个月
you'll be free
那可不就能逃出
from this horrible den of his.
这无常鬼窟了吗
That's nice.
那也是件好事啊
But,
可是
he's still hurt.
他如今这个样子
What if by the time
三个月后
the agreement ends, he is still in a coma.
醒不过来怎么办呀
Impossible.
不会的
He'll be fine by then.
他一定会醒过来的
But, if he wasn't,
可是万一他醒不过来
what will you do?
该怎么办
Stay with him?
你就这么一直守着他呀
He was hurt
他是为了救我
because of me!
才变成现在这样的
I know.
是 我知道
But you should also
可是你也得
have your own life.
为自己打算呀
If...
那万一
he...
他
you know,
那
will you waste your life on a vegetable?
你就给他守活寡吗
Bah.
呸
Nonsense.
胡说什么呢
Spite the bad luck away, now!
你快呸呸呸 呸呸呸
Since you're a fake couple,
你们俩既然是假夫妻
you really should
不管他怎么样
think for yourself from now on.
那你都得为自己打算呀
Look,
你想啊
if you get back to your home
日后你回到颜府
as an abandoned woman,
若是你做个和离的弃妇
your father's wife
那你家大夫人
and your siblings
还有那个兄弟姐妹们
would make your life hell.
他们还能给你好日子过
You and your mom
那你和金姨娘
would be
不得天天的
maltreated by them.
受到各种眼色排挤啊
I think you'd better
我觉得不如
marry another good man.
你找好一个再嫁的良人
C'mon,
不是 垂垂
what are you talking about?
你在说什么呀
The Ministry of Justice?
刑部
It seems that nobody
我觉得刑部
there is marriage material.
好像没什么好人再嫁了
Jiang Langxing!
江郎行
How about him?
要不你考虑一下江郎行
Though he always
江郎行这个人吧
keeps
平日里
a straight face and boring
虽然是整天臭着个脸
as a breathing tombstone,
规行矩步
[he's still a nice man.]
但是他的确是个好人
[Even cute, sometimes.]
有时候还挺可爱的
[Choose him!]
可以
You want me to marry Jiang Langxing?
你要把江郎行推给我
Isn't he nice?
他不好吗
Alright.
好吧
Let me think about it.
那我再想想
Oh, yes!
我想到了一个
A better choice!
更合适的人选
Chief Inspector!
异良帅
[Yes, he's]
徐帅这个人吧
[born humble,]
他虽然出身草莽
[but he's tall and strong,]
但是他高大威猛
also generous.
为人还豪气
If you couldn't be
你要是做不成
Mrs. Shen,
沈家的大夫人
it would be nice
那你做异良帅的夫人
to be his wife.
那也是很威风的呀
[He is kind.]
徐大哥他是个好人
[But there is no]
但我跟他
that kind of flame between us.
并没有什么私情
Stop finding
垂垂你不要
a new husband for me.
再乱点鸳鸯了
You can always set off the right flame.
私情是可以培养的呀
He will be
徐大帅的面相
a great husband.
他一看就是
You can see it on his face.
特别会疼夫人的
Isn't it lovely?
那多好呀
Much better than
那总比跟着那个
the White Death who's always
整天气死你的
infuriate you.
白无常强吧
I'm injured,
沈某只是伤了
not died.
不是死了
Shen Du,
沈渡
you are awake!
你醒了
Slow down.
慢点慢点
Take it slow.
慢点
Lu Chuichui.
陆垂垂
Stop meddling with our lives
还轮不到你跑到我府上
at my place!
来指手画脚的
Get out!
滚出去
Xing,
六娘
I'll be outside.
我在外面等你啊
You...
你
Slow down.
慢点
when did you wake up?
什么时候醒的
Just now.
刚刚
All of a sudden,
你刚刚
you woke out of...
嚯的一下你就
Yes,
我刚刚就是
all of a sudden.
嚯的一下醒过来
- Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
If it weren't for you,
如果不是你
I wouldn't have been killed
我早就死在
by Chen Huo'e.
陈火蛾的手里了
Because of me, you've suffered so much.
还害你受了这么重的伤
It's not you who should be blamed,
错的是陈火蛾
but her.
不是你
Anyway, you treated
我身上这些伤
my injuries, remember?
不也是你治的吗
Where is her body?
陈火蛾的尸身呢
You're wounded badly back then,
当时你受了伤
Jing Lin and I were busy bringing you back.
我和景林着急带你回来
Somebody seized the chance
陈火蛾的尸首
to take that away.
被人暗中带走了
Jing Lin has looked into it all night.
景林连夜去查了
We believe that
推测是御察司的人
the Imperial Inspectorate did it.
把他的尸首带走的
Lai Luozhi!
来罗织
I believe that
我在想
Chen Huo'e was at large
陈火蛾此前失踪
for Lai Luozhi's neglect.
本就是来罗织的失责
Then, his minions
如今御察司的人
stole
又去把
her body away.
陈火蛾的尸首偷走
He must be planning something.
恐怕必有图谋
Time for us to hunker down
我们不妨先等等
in anticipation,
以静制动
to see what they would do.
且看他们会有什么动作
You should take some rest.
你先好好休息一下
[Sir,]
管家
[my husband has woken up.]
大阁领已经醒了
[Go get the doctor, please.]
你快去请府医再来看看
[How fancy!]
郎君醒了
[Thank God!]
谢天谢地
[It's a miracle!]
菩萨保佑
[Hurry! Fetch the doctor!]
快快快 快去请府医
Xing.
六娘
Chuichui.
垂垂
Finally, you're here.
你可算出来了
What's wrong with
你快去管管
the servants in this mansion?
这沈府的人吧
I'm Mrs. Shen's friend,
夫人的好姐妹来了
yet they refuse to serve anything to me.
连顿饭都不管
Miss Lu,
陆大小姐
are you short on money?
你是不是缺银子了
I've developed an addiction
你是不知道
to the new play
那芙蓉园的新戏
staged in the Furong theater.
可太好看了
The actors are marvelous!
那伶人演得那叫一绝呀
So, I spent
我这不就
all my money there.
零花钱给人打赏去了嘛
Now, my father refuses
我爹又把我的零花钱
to pay my bills,
给我停掉了
and my salary is still on the way.
我这月的月例又还没发
So...
所以
You're my best friend,
都是好姐妹一场
can you invite me for lunch?
你就说管不管饭吧
Mr Shen!
沈老管家
[Yes, ma'am.]
来了来了
What can I do for you?
夫人有何吩咐
Prepare some food
麻烦您给垂垂
for Chuichui
还有云雀姑娘
and Yun Que.
安排一下用饭吧
And, pack some of them for me,
另备一份食盒
the master and I will eat in his bedroom.
我带回主屋
Yes, ma'am.
好嘞
Yan Xing,
颜六娘
we haven't eaten together for ages.
我们好不容易一次共饭
Can't you stay?
你都不陪我啊
Shen Du is confined to bed.
沈渡伤患在床
He needs to be taken care of.
刚醒过来离不了人
He has so many servants.
那沈府那么多人
He doesn't need you as I do.
又不缺你一个了
Yun Que,
云雀
you said yourself,
你不是嚷嚷着
that you want to marry the Whit...
要嫁给白无
Shen Du.
沈 沈渡的吗
He's in pain.
人沈渡在那儿重伤了
Why don't you go look after him?
你不去表功
Why are you staying here, with me?
倒在这儿来躲清闲
I just give up.
看透了
You finally believe the White Death
白无常不是好人
will never be a good husband?
不是良配啊
After all these fusses,
不过这段时间
I figured that
我倒是看清楚一件事
Yan Xing,
颜幸
you don't love him, why would you
你志不在沈夫人
waste the rest of your life here?
何必在沈府耽误一辈子
Exactly!
说得好
You are
你们两个现在
in Shen Du's mansion,
还在沈府呢
keep it down!
小声点
Ma'am,
夫人
the lunch box you asked for.
您要的吃食备好了
Guards!
来人
Yes, master.
在
Tell all our men,
传我令
since the game begins,
既然都已入局
let's give them
那就再给他们
more fun, shall we?
加点料
Right?
是吧是吧
Believe me,
我跟你说呀
he's gorgeous!
他真的是超好看
Yes, he is.
你说得太对了
I'd never thought
不过一顿饭的工夫
you can become so close
你们二人
after a simple meal.
就变得如此亲密了
Yun Que and I
我跟云雀妹妹相见甚欢
hit it off. She's like
一见如故
the sister I never had.
亲似姐妹
We both agree that only girls
我和垂垂姐一致认为
would truly understand each other.
只有女子才真的懂女子
We should never let others
我们的命运
decide our future.
不应该被别人决定
That's right.
就是
We should
我们应该
figure it out on ourselves.
自己寻找前路在何方
So,
所以
we are inviting you
我们决定
to Mingsheng Temple with us,
邀请你
asking gods' blessing
三日后
on our marriage, three days later.
一同前去明圣观求姻缘
Mingsheng Temple?
明圣观
Marriage?
求姻缘
You wouldn't be Mrs. Shen
你不会真的想
forever, would you?
一辈子做沈夫人吧
Although I give up
虽然我对沈渡
on Shen Du,
失去了兴趣
you are not
难道你跟沈渡
close with him.
就是同气连枝的好夫妻
You agreed to leave him in three months, right?
三月之期不作数了
Yeah, right.
当然作数
Then, why are you hesitating?
那你扭捏什么
You are not
你不会是
in love with the White Death, are you?
爱上白无常了吧
I will leave him
等约定之期到了
when the time comes.
我自然会离开他
But I want to build a career.
我只是志在功名
So, marriage is not in my plan for my future.
没有想过再嫁之事罢了
You can always have a career and a husband.
姻缘和功名又不相冲
Yes.
就是啊
Three days later,
三日之后
we'll go to Mingsheng Temple,
反正我们先去明圣观
asking for gods' blessing nonetheless.
求了姻缘再说
Hear, hear.
就这么定了
Oh, and,
对了
Newly-made candied fruits
我屋子里
are piling up at my home.
有新腌渍的果子
I can't have them all.
最近都吃不下
Do you want to have a bite?
请你去尝尝
Yes, please!
想吃想吃
Let's go.
走 走
Bye.
走了
Don't miss me.
不要太想我了
Looking forward to your little trip?
这么重视
Should I give you a hand?
要不要为夫帮你挑
What?
啥
Should I pick something out for you?
要不要我帮你挑
Right,
也是
you are still healing.
你如今身受重伤
I shouldn't leave you alone at home.
我丢下你外出确实不妥
I'll get someone
那我等一下
to send those dresses
就把那几条衣裙
to Chuichui,
给垂垂送过去
let her make her own decision.
让她自己挑选
I'll not go with her.
三日后我就不去了
You're doing this for Lu Chuichui?
这裙子是替陆垂垂挑的
Yeah.
对啊
She'll stay with us for a couple of days.
她这几日暂住沈府
But
可惜
my dresses are
我的衣裙颜色
all so plain.
都不够明艳
She wouldn't like them.
恐怕她不会喜欢
You should go have fun with your friends.
既然是姐妹出游
Don't worry about me, darling.
夫人不用担心为夫
Our servants will take good care of me.
沈府还不至于没人可用
And, three days later,
至于三日之后
I'll be healthy enough
我应该也能下床了
to go with you.
到时候便与你们一同
No. Please don't.
不用不用不用
You hurt badly,
你受了这么重的伤
need to have a lot of rest.
得多养些时日才行
Go back to sleep.
你先歇着啊
I really spend
我不就是
too much time in the theater.
多看了两场戏嘛
Why did I doze off?
怎么就睡着了呢
It must be
一定是那个
the play's fault. I was lost in the story
那个戏文太好看了
and
然后
I...
我就
It's alright.
没事没事
Today is
今日可真是
such a good day!
阳光明媚
The sun is so bright!
晴空万里啊
I'm doomed.
完了
You're alive or dead?
是人是鬼啊
Dead.
是鬼
Why are you afraid of ghosts?
鬼有什么好怕的
Ghosts were ordinary people.
生前也都是人罢了
Though you said so, I'm still terrified.
你是不怕 我怕呀
I'm so scared!
是鬼就怕死了
I did nothing wrong to you.
冤有头债有主
Go find the one who hurt you, please.
谁欠你的你找谁去
Go away, please.
我求求你走开
You seemed to be
之前在墓地时
braver when
怎么没发现
we were in the cemetery.
你胆子这么小啊
Oh, it's you.
是你啊
Maskman,
鬼面兄
it's strange.
好奇怪啊
I was horrified moments ago.
明明我刚才还那么害怕
But once I know
可是你一坐到我旁边
you're with me,
这里突然变得
I'm not afraid anymore.
好像不那么害怕了
Maybe because
可能因为
the ghosts also loathe me and go away.
这里的鬼魅都怕我吧
Why abase yourself?
你干吗妄自菲薄
Just stating the fact.
事实而已
I'm
这世上
abominated by everything
别说是人
in the world,
就是魑魅魍魉
no matter if they're alive or dead.
也唯恐避我不及
Nonsense.
你胡说
Don't be so harsh on yourself.
为什么要说得那么吓人
You're a nice man.
你明明很好
Believe me,
你看
fairies that
就像是
couldn't be seen
在这虚空中
by mortal eyes
看不到的小仙人
are keen to be your friends.
都想跟你一起做朋友呢
I'll show you.
不信你看
Just look.
看好了
Oh, dear fairy,
小仙人 小仙人
will you befriend
你愿不愿意和鬼面兄
with maskman?
做好朋友啊
If you will,
你要是愿意的话
please transfer yourself
你就从这个碗里
from this bowl
跳到这个碗里
to this bowl.
好不好呀
Oh, you want to hear
你要鬼面兄
maskman invite you in person?
亲自来邀请你呀
So, maskman,
鬼面兄
please invite
请你邀请一下
the fairy.
我们的小仙人
Please join us, dear fairy.
请小仙人一起
See?
你看
It agrees.
小仙人答应了
Since fairies
小仙人都愿意
love you
和你做朋友
and want to play with you,
和你一起玩游戏
you must be the most lovable person.
你是最讨人喜欢的
Everybody loves you.
所有人都会喜欢你
It's alright.
好了好了
Don't be sad.
不哭了啊
You're the most lovable boy in the world.
你是最讨人喜欢的
Everybody loves you.
所有人都会喜欢你
They must love you.
而且他们必须都喜欢你
You're right.
是啊
Fairy,
小仙人
since you're also
既然你也是
Lu Chuichui's friend,
陆垂垂的朋友
can you do me a favour?
能不能请你帮我个忙啊
It agrees.
小仙人答应了
What?
怎么
It's scary?
被吓到了
You are
你呀
such an odd creature.
好生奇怪
Unflappable in a late-night cemetery, yet
深夜的墓地不怕
so easy to be frightened by small things.
却这么容易被吓到
Yet, you showed no fear
说你胆子小怕鬼吧
to my ugly musk.
却不怕我这一副鬼面
Because there's nothing to be afraid of.
那墓地有什么好怕的
The cemetery is the resting place of
那墓地里躺的是我最亲
my dearest mother.
最想见的娘亲
And you...
而鬼面兄你呢
you're wearing a mask
你不愿意摘面具
to cover your birthmark.
只是因为脸上的胎记
Why should I be afraid of that?
那也没什么好怕的呀
Oh, right!
对了
I heard that
我还打听到
golden rings
说那个金戒指
could not remove
祛除胎记的法子
one's birthmark.
好像没那么管用
You should stop using it.
要不你还是别用了
It would be a pity
万一脸给蹭花了
if the ring cut your face.
那就不好了
Why?
怎么
Are you taking your ring back?
你要把金戒指要回去
No, you keep it.
你留着吧
If I can't get rid of those marks,
那我祛不掉胎记
I'll never get the nerve to
便永远不敢在你面前
take off my mask in front of you.
露出真容了
Don't be.
怎么会啊
It's not your fault.
有胎记又不是你的错
Besides, one's character
而且容颜是什么样子
is never determined
那也不能影响
by one's appearance.
一个人内心的美好啊
I believe
我觉得
our appearance is
人的相貌
like
就好比
makeup
戏曲中的
of actors and actresses.
生旦净末的扮相
It's only a small part of the character.
只是人物的一部分
Then, what do you think of me?
那你觉得我这扮相
Am I virtuous?
是善
Am I evil?
是恶
Good or bad?
是忠是奸
I'll tell you
等你什么时候
when you take off
愿意摘下面具
your mask.
我再告诉你
What if
如果
you lose interest
如果我摘了面具
in my appearance,
你却不愿看了
what should I do?
又该如何
Don't worry.
你放心好了
I gave you the ring in hopes of
我送你金戒指呢
helping you remove your birthmark.
是希望你能够祛除胎记
But, I don't care
但是你能不能祛除
if you can remove it or not.
现在已经不重要了
Because either way, I already
因为我早就已经把你
look you as a dear friend of mine.
当成朋友了
I would never judge a book by its cover.
我肯定不会以貌取人
Just, take it off.
你摘吧
I will.
那我摘了
Lai Luozhi...
来罗织
Lu Chuichui.
陆垂垂
Today,
今日
I revealed my secret to you.
我既以真容待你
Whether you're frightened or not,
无论你有没有被吓到
please keep it for me.
都请你替我保守秘密
Don't tell it
不要将此事
to another soul.
告诉第三人
Hope you can
记得你答应我的
keep your promise.
不要食言
I believe you.
我信你
What are you thinking?
想什么呢
Nothing.
没什么
Well,
那个
look,
六娘你看
there are so many people here
这多少佳人淑女
all asking for
才子墨客
a perfect marriage.
都到这儿来求姻缘
You're here.
来了
What a coincidence!
好巧啊
You're also here for a suitable match?
你们也来求姻缘来了
Why?
怎么
You don't think
只允许
you are the only ones who need it.
你们刑部女官来得
And people like us
就不允许
shouldn't require a happy marriage?
我们异良人来了吗
Of course not.
当然不是了
I'm just saying,
我只是感叹
how fascinating
这个缘分
fate works.
怎会如此巧妙呀
Right, Xing?
是不是啊 六娘
Stop it.
别说了
Let's go.
快走吧
Where to?
走哪儿去
Like you said, asking gods' blessing.
你不是说去求姻缘吗
Askin...
去
Really?!
想不到啊 江古板
You're also in want of a wife!
你也有这个诉求啊
Who'd thought it!
看不出来啊 江古板
Alright.
行吧行吧
You are old enough
想你也一把年纪了
to take interest
想找个书本外的颜如玉
in girls, not books.
也是人之常情
I'll go with you!
那我陆垂垂就陪你
Since you're interested, I'll do it
舍命陪君子
Xing,
六娘
you go talk with the general,
你好好和徐帅聊一聊啊
I'll be back soon.
我去去就回
Let's go.
走走走
I believe you rarely
六娘也很少来
visit this temple.
明圣观游玩吧
Would you like to join me?
一起逛逛
Have fun.
你们去你们去
Leave me alone.
别管我
[Shen Du,]
沈渡
[you must drink it up.]
这碗药一定要喝
[Visiting the Temple for a new marriage?]
明圣观求姻缘
Jing Lin.
景林
Yes, sir.
大阁领
Xiangren.
徐大哥
What are you trying to say?
你可是有事要说
Xing,
六娘
I overheard Lu Chuichui
那天我无意间听到
discussing your marriage.
陆垂垂说起你的婚事
[That's insane.]
这不是开玩笑嘛
[How can a woman request a divorce?]
女子怎么能提和离呢
[Why not?]
怎么不能提了
The law says that
你可别忘了
divorce due to
依大苍律法
disharmony
若夫妻
does not require
不相安谐而和离者
punishment.
不坐
Besides,
再说了
they've never...
他们又没有那个
slept together.
那个夫妻之实
They agreed to separate long ago.
他们都约好了要和离了
[Anyhow,]
反正
[I already told her]
我早就让她作打算了
to find another one.
另寻良人
But, it's a shame
只可惜啊
that there is no suitable man
你们这异良人的人
from your place
还有刑部的人
and the Minstry of Justice.
都没有合适的
except for General Xu.
除了徐帅
Some day, I swear
陆垂垂这张嘴
I'll shut Lu Chuichui up for good.
早晚有一天撕了